Guide to the Free to Dance Records, 1987-2004
American Dance Festival Archives Durham, N.C., USA
Free to Dance records 1987-2004
American Dance Festival Archives Box 90772 Durham, North Carolina, 27708-0772 USA Phone: 919-684-6402 Fax: 919-684-5459 Email: adfarchives@americandancefestival.org
American Dance Festival, John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, Thirteen/WNET New York
96.34 Linear Feet
Free to Dance: The African-American Presence in Modern Dance was a three-part television documentary co-produced by the American Dance Festival and the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts in association with Thirteen/WNET New York. The series aired on PBS' Great Performances: Dance in America in 2001. It chronicled the role of African-American choreographers and dancers in the development of modern dance as an American art form.
The collection includes film, video, sound recordings, oral histories, interview transcripts, business records, photographs, clippings, and research materials created or collected during the production of the three-part television documentary Free to Dance.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Patrons must sign the Acknowledgement of Legal Responsibility and Privacy Rights form before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Access to film, videotapes, or audiotapes in this collection requires the use of reference copies. To arrange for the creation of reference copies, if none exist, please contact American Dance Festival Archives.
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Provenance
The Free to Dance Records were received by the American Dance Festival Archives as transfers in 2000-2004.
Historical Note
Free to Dance: The African-American Presence in Modern Dance was a three-part television documentary co-produced by the American Dance Festival and the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts in association with Thirteen/WNET New York. The series aired on PBS' Great Performances: Dance in America in 2001 and won an Emmy for Outstanding Cultural and Artistic Programming-Long Form. It chronicled the role of African-American choreographers and dancers in the development of modern dance as an American art form. Dance masterpieces by African-American choreographers were filmed expressly for the series, including the works of Katherine Dunham (Barrelhouse Blues), Pearl Primus (Strange Fruit), Donald McKayle (Rainbow 'Round My Shoulder), Talley Beatty (Mourner's Bench), Bill T. Jones (D-Man in the Waters), Alvin Ailey (Revelations), and many others.
Free to Dance was an outgrowth of the American Dance Festival's Black Tradition in American Modern Dance (BTAMD) program. Initiated in 1987 to preserve, present, and interpret significant dances by African-American choreographers, BTAMD reconstructed and presented twenty-three dances in danger of being lost. BTAMD's national touring initiative presented performances throughout the US by African-American dance companies, including Chuck Davis' African American Dance Ensemble, Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, Philadanco, and Cleo Parker Robinson Dance Ensemble. Scholars touring with the companies contextualized and interpreted the cultural and aesthetic significance of the dances in panel discussions.
The success of the BTAMD project led to the creation of Free to Dance, and the American Dance Festival began fund raising efforts in 1993. Fund raising, research, and conceptual development continued through 1997. Full production commenced in 1998, including scripting, securing the rights to archival footage and photos, and the filming of interviews, performances, and scene recreations. Editing was completed in 2001.
Collection Overview
The collection includes business records, grant proposals, correspondence, film, video, sound recordings, oral histories, interview transcripts, photographs, clippings, and research materials created or collected during the production of the three-part television documentary Free to Dance.
The bulk of the Free to Dance Collection dates from 1998 to 2001, when technical production of the series took place; however, the collection also includes grant proposals and early project development documentation dating back to 1987, as well as some correspondence and financial information created after its air date in 2001.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Ailey, Alvin
Beatty, Talley
Dunham, Katherine
Jones, Bill T.
McKayle, Donald, 1930-
Primus, Pearl
American Dance Festival
Free to Dance
Choreographers -- United States
African American dance
Dance -- United States
Modern dance -- United States
Contents of Collection
- Administrative Records, 1987-2004 and undated (Box 1)
  Arranged into six subseries: General Administration, Personnel, Finance, Grants and Fund Raising, Licensing and Agreements, and Promotion.
  - General Administration, 1997-2000, 7 folders
    Contains information pertaining to office management, including general policies and procedures, equipment purchases and rentals, and staff contact information.
    - Computers: Purchase and Rental, 1997-1998, 2000
    - Computers: Maintenance and Use, 1998-1999
    - Materials for the Arts (Office Furniture), 1994-1998
    - Policies and Procedures, 1998-2000
    - Stationery and Logo, 1997-1998
    - Telephone Service, 1997-2000
    - Telephone System, 1997-1999
  - Personnel, 1994-2001, 9 folders
    RESTRICTED. Contains salary negotiations, contracts, and employment dates, as well as memoranda and notes regarding employees and their assignments and schedules.
    - Chodorov, Stephan, 1995-2001
    - Diamond, Matthew, 1995, 1998
    - Grumann, Amy, 1998-2000
    - Lacy, M. Davis, 1993-1998
    - Lambie, Jenna, 1998
    - Lenzer, Donald, 1998-1999
    - Ove, Horace, and Patrick, Maria, 1998-1999
    - Other Employees, 1994, 1998
    - Management Memoranda and Notes, 1997-2000
  - Finance, 1987-2004 and undated, 5 linear feet
    Contains financial records created by the American Dance Festival's Director of the Finance and Administration during the production of Free to Dance.
    - Accounts Payable, 1994-2001, 2 linear feet
      Contains check requests, invoices, receipts, and correspondence regarding archival repositories, rental facilities, FTD staff, consultants, film crews, and other service providers. The Accounts Payable series also contains signed licensing agreements for the use of footage and music.
      - A, 1998-2000
      - A&B Courier, 1999-2000
      - Abelcine Tech, 1998
      - Adelman, Alan, 1998-1999
      - Arndt, Prudence, 1998-1999
      - ASC (Audio Services Co.), 1998
      - Auchincloss, Malcolm, 1998-1999
      - B, 1998-2001
      - BBC Worldwide, 1998, 2000
      - C, 1995, 1998-2000
      - Chambliss, Candace, 1998
      - Chertok Associates, 1998-2000
      - Chick Chack Messenger, 1998-2000
      - Chodorov, Stephan, 1995, 1999
      - Cinepost, 1998
      - Consultants, 1995-1996, 1998-2000 (2 folders)
      - D, 1998-2000
      - Diamond, Matthew, 1999
      - Donald Lenzer Films, 1998-1999
      - DuArt Film Lab, 1994-1995, 1998-1999, 1999-2000 (3 folders)
      - E, 1998-2000
      - Educational Broadcasting Corporation, 1999-2001
      - Elliott, Doreen, 1998-2000
      - Eyeball on the Floor, 2000
      - F, 1998-2000
      - Federal Express, 1999-2000
      - Film Center, 1998-1999
      - Firethorn Productions, 1994-1995, 2000-2001 (2 folders)
      - Fisher, William, 1998
      - Frame:Runner, Inc., 2000
      - Frame Shop, 2000
      - Fussell, Ed, 1998-1999
      - G, 1998-2000
      - Greene, Denise, 1999-2000
      - Grumann, Amy, 1999-2000
      - H, 1998-2000
      - Hallick, Ned, 1998-1999
      - Harris-Chewning Inc., 1998-1999
      - Henninger Video, 2000
      - Historic Films, 1998, 2000-2001
      - I-J, 1998-2000
      - Jefferson, Kristin, 1999-2000
      - John E. Allen (JEA), Inc., 1998-2000
      - John Zecca Location, 1999-2000
      - Jones, Lewanne, 1998
      - Juett, Marci, 1998-2000
      - K, 1998-2000
      - Karimakwenda, Tererai, 1998-1999
      - Kaufmann, Amy, 1998
      - Klein, Randy, 2000
      - L, 1998-2000
      - Lacy, Madison Davis, 1997-2000 (3 folders)
      - Lambie, Jennifer (Jenna), 1998-2000 (2 folders)
      - Lefcourt, Karen, 1999
      - Liberty Lighting, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
      - Linson, Valerie, 1998-1999
      - M, 1998-2000
      - MacDonald, Annette, 1999-2000
      - McDowell Media Services, 1999-2000
      - Michaud, Rachelle, 2000
      - Miller, Peter, 1998-1999
      - MPI Media Group, 1999-2000
      - Museum of the City of New York, 1999-2000
      - Music Rights, A-D
      - Music Rights, E-M
      - Music Rights, O-S
      - Music Rights, T-Z
      - N, 1998-2000
      - New York Public Library, 2000-2001
      - New York Public Library Dance Collection Film Fund, 1999-2000
      - O, 1998-2000
      - One Art Productions, 1998-2000
      - Ove, Horace, 1998-1999
      - P, 1998-2000
      - Pathe Television, 1998-1999 (2 folders)
      - Patrick, Maria, 1998-1999
      - Patrick, Maria, Reimbursement, 1998-2000 (2 folders)
      - Pearson, Kier, 1999-2000
      - Petty Cash, 1998-2000 (7 folders)
      - Petty Cash Summary Reports, 1999-2000
      - Producers Library, 1998-2000
      - Q, 1998-2000
      - Quill Corp, 1998-2000
      - R, 1998-2000
      - Regal University Hotel, 1998-1999
      - Reichman, Rachel, 1998-2000
      - Romeo, John, 1998
      - S, 1998-2000
      - Sakakeeny, Tahnit, 1998
      - Shapiro, Jada, 2000
      - SnowBird Corp, 1998-2000
      - Sony Music, 2000
      - Squires, Eugene B., 1999-2000
      - Steadi Systems, 1995, 1999
      - Sumner, Andrea, 1998
      - T, 1998-2000
      - Tape Company, 1999-2000
      - Telephone Service: Bell Atlantic, 1997-1998
      - Telephone Service: Frontier, 1998-1999
      - Telephone Service: Global Crossing, 2000
      - Telephone Service: TCN, 1999-2000
      - Travel, 1998-2002 (2 folders)
      - Twentieth Century Fox, 2000
      - U, 1998-2000
      - University Products, 1998-2000
      - V, 1998-2000 (Box 3)
      - Victor, Jeffrey, 1998-1999
      - Video D Studios, 1998-2000
      - VidiPax, 1999
      - W-Z, 1998-2000
      - WGBH Educational Foundation, 1999-2001
      - WRS Motion Picture, 1998-2000
      - Wyatt, Karen, 1998-1999
      - Zucker, Adam, 1998-2000
    - Work Orders, 1998-1999, 2 folders
      Work Orders were used in the early research phase by the archival producers and researchers to account for footage transfers and licensing fees.
      - Work Orders, Preliminary Research, 1998-1999 (2 folders)
    - Financial Reports, 1995-2001 and undated, 22 folders
      - Budgets, Drafts: Film Shoots, Personnel, Show Four, "School," 1995-1999
      - General Ledger, 1997-2001 (6 folders)
      - Income Summaries, 1999-2000 and undated
      - Licensing Expenses, 2000
      - Summaries of Expenses, 1999-2000
      - Weekly Reports, 1998-2001 and undated (10 folders)
      - Memoranda, 1998-2001
      - Memoranda: Accounts Payable, Budgets, Policy, 1998-2001
  - Grants and Fund Raising, 1987-2004, 1.5 linear feet
    Includes grant proposals, critiques, correspondence, budgets, and other financial information pertaining to the eight major funders of Free to Dance: the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, the Ford Foundation, the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, the National Black Programming Consortium, the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Humanities, and the Public Broadcasting Service and its local New York affiliate Thirteen WNET, which replaced WETA (Washington, DC). This subseries also contains information pertaining to other fund raising efforts, especially in relation to international distribution rights and solicitations for outreach and education funding.
    - Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1995-2001, 8 folders
      - Budgets, 1996-2001
      - Contracts, 1997, 1999
      - Correspondence, 1995-1999, 2001 (5 folders)
      - Proposal, 1997
    - Ford Foundation, 1993-2001, 8 folders
      - Budgets, 1994-2001
      - Correspondence, 1993-2000 (4 folders)
      - Interim Reports, 1998-1999
      - Proposals, 1994, 1999 (2 folders)
    - John. F. Kennedy Center, 1996-2001
      - Correspondence, 1996-2001
    - National Black Programming Consortium, 1996-2004, 3 folders
      - Contracts, 2000-2001
      - Correspondence, 1999-2004 (3 folders) (Box 4)
      - Final Financial Reports, 2001
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 1994-2001, 9 folders
      - Budgets, 1995-2001, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1994-2001, (4 folders)
      - Instructions, Forms, etc., 1994-1995
      - Proposals, 1995, 1998
      - Proposal drafts by S'thembile West, 1994-1995
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1987-2003, 14 folders
      - Budgets, 1995-2000 and undated
      - Correspondence, 1994-2003 (7 folders)
      - Federal Cash Transaction Reports, 1997-2000
      - Instructions and Forms, 1988-1997
      - Proposals, 1987, 1995-1996 (3 folders)
      - Proposal drafts, 1995
    - Public Broadcasting Service, 1995-2001, 2 folders
      - Contracts, 1999
      - Correspondence, 1995-2001
    - WETA, 1996-2000
      - Correspondence, 1996-2000
    - WNET Thirteen, 1996-2002, 3 folders
      - Contract, 2000
      - Correspondence, 1996-2002 (2 folders)
    - Grants, General, 1994-2002, 7 folders
      - Budgets, 1994-1999 and undated (4 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1996-2000 and undated (Box 5)
      - Correspondence and Memos, 1994-2001
      - Proposal Drafts, 1994 and undated
    - Fund Raising, 1995-2000, 4 folders
      - International Distribution, 1999-2000
      - Outreach and Education, 1999-2000
      - Solicitations for International Co-Producers, 1995-1997
      - Solicitations, 1996
  - Licenses, Releases, and Agreements, 1998-2003, .5 linear feet
    Contains documents regarding the reproduction rights for original and archival materials. Related material can also be found in the Licensing Expenses folders under Financial Reports in the Finance Subseries.
    - Appearances and Performances, 1998-2001 and undated, 13 folders
      - Dayton Contemporary Dance Company
      - Dunham, Katherine
      - Cleo Parker Robinson Dance Company
      - Edna Guy/Ruth St. Denis
      - Forces of Nature
      - Hampton University
      - Jones, Bill T.
      - Noble Douglas Dance Company
      - Oral History Interviews
      - Philadanco
      - Thompson, Clive
      - Related Information, 2000 and undated
      - Correspondence, Internal, 1998-2001 and undated
    - Footage, undated, 6 folders
      Footage agreements were either materials options, which guaranteed the right to use certain clips at a pre-determined price, or fully executed licenses, which were executed after footage was selected for use.
      Materials options are arranged alphabetically by licensor in the first three folders. Final licensing agreements are arranged by show in the last three folders.
      - A-K
      - M-P
      - R-W
      - Show 1
      - Show 2
      - Show 3
    - Music, 2000-2003 and undated, 4 folders
      - Correspondence, Internal 2000
      - Research, 2000
      - Shows 1-3
      - Tele Cinema, 2001-2003
    - Tallies of Agreements, 2000 and undated
    - Visual Art, undated, 3 folders
      - Show 1
      - Show 2
      - Show 3
    - Voice-Overs and Narration, undated, 2 folders
      - Miguel, Jewel
      - Underwood, Blair
- Production Records, 1994-2001 and undated (Box 5)
  Arranged into three subseries: Pre-Production Files, Production Files, and Post-Production Files.
  - Pre-Production Files, 1994-2001 and undated, 6.25 linear feet
    Includes correspondence and documents produced by Gerald E. Myers, the director of ADF's humanities programs, and the team of scholars he gathered to advise the writers and producers. Also includes scheduling and planning memos, treatments, outlines, drafts of scripts, secondary sources research files, and production management records.
    - Correspondence, 1995-2000, 2 folders
      - Consultants, 1995-1998
      - Internal, 1998-2000
    - Interview Preparation Files, 1995-2000, 36 folders
      Contains notes, correspondence, memoranda, and drafts of interview questions.
      - Interviewees and Potential Interviewees, 1998-1999
      - Show 2, 1998
      - Show 3, 1998
      - A-G, undated
      - Beatty, Talley, 1995
      - Berry, April, 1998
      - Brown, Ron K., 1999
      - Chief Bey, 1999
      - de Lavallade, Carmen, 1998
      - Dinizulu, Alice, 1999
      - Gottschild, Brenda Dixon, 1998
      - Grona, Eugene Von, 1995
      - H-P, undated
      - Haskins, James, 1999
      - Heard, Marcia, 1999
      - Holder, Boscoe, 1998
      - Holder, Geoffrey, 1999
      - Lawson, Cristyne, 1998
      - Lewitzky, Bella, 1998
      - McBurnie, Beryl, 1998
      - McKayle, Donald, 1995, 1998
      - Nash, Joe, 1998
      - Nettleford, Rex,1999
      - Osumare, Halifu, 1999
      - Pomare, Eleo, 1998
      - Powell, Richard, 1999
      - Queenan, Charles, 1999
      - R-Y, undated
      - Romero, Carmencita, 1999
      - Richardson, Dorene, 1998 (Box 6)
      - Russell, Maude, 1998
      - Sheldon, Dean, Notes,1998
      - Solomons, Jr., Gus, 1999
      - Thompson, Clive, 1998
      - Wasserman, Dale, 1998
      - West, S'tembile, 1999
    - Location Scouting, 1998 and undated, 2 folders
      - Hampton, VA, 1998
      - New York, NY, 1998 and undated
    - Production Management, 1994-2001, 2 folders
      - Notes, circa 1997
      - Schedules and Planning, 1994, 1997-2000
      - Updates from Series Producer to Executive Producers, 1997-2001
    - "School", 1997-1998, 2 folders
      - Correspondence, 1997-1998
      - Development and Production, Dec. 1997-Feb. 1998
    - Secondary Sources Research Files, 3.5 linear feet
      RESTRICTED: This material consists of copies of material from other repositories and is not open for research. Contains photocopies of programs, clippings, photographs, magazine articles, book excerpts, books, dissertations, interview transcripts, correspondence, press kits, and related materials used as secondary sources on dance, dancers, choreographers, and twentieth-century history.
      - 92nd Street Y, New York, NY, 1937-1998
      - Africa, Politics and Government: Fanon, Frantz. Toward the African Revolution, 1964
      - African American Dance, 1978-2000 (9 folders)
      - African American Periodicals
        - A-N, 1921, 1950
        - Ebony, 1953
        - Hue, 1952-1954
        - Jet, 1952
        - Messenger, 1919-1927
        - New York Amsterdam News, 1922-1951
        - Notes, 1998
        - Opportunity, 1923
        - Our World, 1920-1955
      - African American Sociology, 1968, 1998, 1989
      - AIDS: Dancers Responding to AIDS, 1988-1996
      - Ailey, Alvin, 1960-1999 and undated (13 folders)
      - Allen, Zita D., 1974-1977 and undated
      - American Dance Festival Black Tradition in American Modern Dance, 1987-1999
      - Anthropology: Zamora, Mario D., Anthropology: An Overview and Other Essays. New Delhi: Reliance Publishing House, 1991
      - B-R, 1946, 1995-1999
      - Baker, Josephine, 1934-1935, 1998
      - Beatty, Talley, 1945-1999 (7 folders)
      - Belafonte, Julie Robinson, circa 1950-1959
      - Brown, Ronald K., circa 1990-1999 (2 folders)
      - Brown, Trisha, 1970-1973
      - Castle, Vernon and Irene, circa 1920-1985
      - Century of Progress International Exposition (1933-1934), 1969, 2000
      - Civilian Conservation Corps, 1969
      - Collins, Janet, 1949-1995
      - Cuyjet, Marion, 1921-1996 (Box 7)
      - Dafora, Asadata, 1934-1998
      - Dance: Bibliography, 1996
      - Dance, History: Lloyd, Margaret, The Borzoi Book of Modern Dance. New York: Dance Horizons, 1949
      - Dance Sociology Course Packet: "Dance, Movement, and Pluralism", Temple University, 1997
      - Davis, Chuck, African American Dance Ensemble (AADE), 1970-1998 (3 folders)
      - de Lavallade, Carmen, 1955, 1958, circa 1980-2000 (2 folders)
      - DeLoatch, Gary, 1982, 1993
      - Destine, Jean Leon, 1950-1979 (2 folders)
      - Dove, Ulysses, 1996, 2000
      - Dunham, Katherine, circa 1910-2000 (36 folders)
      - Dunham, Katherine, 1939, 1979 (Box OS1)
      - Fagan, Garth, 1980-1998 (4 folders) (Box 8)
      - Federal Theatre Project, 1935-1939, 1998-1999 (2 folders)
      - Film Production, Dance, 1996
      - Fort, Syvilla, 1998
      - Goldberg, Jane, 1979-1998
      - Gottschild, Brenda Dixon, 1990, 1995
      - Graham, Martha, 1948-1991
      - Grona, Eugene Von, circa 1930-1995 (6 folders)
      - Guy, Edna, circa 1914-2000 (7 folders)
      - Hampton Institute, Hampton Creative Dance Group, 1914-1945
      - Harlem, NY, circa 1930-1949, 1990 (4 folders)
      - Holder, Geoffrey, 1954-1998
      - Horton, Lester, 1937-1995
      - House of Flowers (play), circa 1950-1959, 1982 (2 folders)
      - Hurston, Zora Neale, 1992-1998 (2 folders)
      - Index of Dancers: Towers, Deirdre. Dance Film and Video Guide, 1991
      - International Association of Blacks in Dance Conferences, 1994-1999
      - Jacob's Pillow, Photographs: Lester Horton Dancers, Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn, circa 1930-1959
      - Jamaica (musical comedy), 1957
      - Jamison, Judith, 1971-1998
      - Jazz Dance, 1968, 1978
      - Jefferson, Margo, 1995-1998
      - Jones, Bill T./Arnie Zane Dance Company, 1989-1994 (2 folders)
      - Jooss, Kurt, Jooss Ballet, circa 1947
      - Kitt, Eartha, 1955-1956, 1989
      - Lawson, Christyne, 1946, circa 1950-1959
      - Lynching, circa 1930-1939
      - Martin, John, 1936-1994 (2 folders)
      - Maslow, Sophie, 1983
      - McBurnie, Beryl, Little Carib Company, 1951-1998 (2 folders)
      - McIntyre, Dianne, 1974-1998, 2 folders
      - McKayle, Donald, circa 1950-1998 ( 8 folders)
      - Mitchell, Arthur, circa 1960-1979 (2 folders)
      - Modern Dance, 1940-1999 (3 folders) (Box 9)
      - Modernism (Art), United States, 20th century, 1960-1987
      - Moore, Peter, 1963-1993
      - Morgan, Barbara, 1983
      - Nash, Joe, 1973-1995
      - Nettleford, Rex, 1983, 1990
      - New Dance Group, 1933-2000 (5 folders)
      - New York City Photographs, circa 1920-1939
      - Nicholas Brothers: Hill, Constance V., Brothers in Rhythm. New York: Oxford University Press, 1999
      - Nicks, Walter, circa 1930-1939
      - Olantunji, Babatunde, 1998-1999
      - Pageants, circa 1920-1929, 1997
      - Philadanco, 1998-1999
      - Photographers, Dance, 1999
      - Pilcher, Evelyn, circa 1930-1949
      - Pins and Needles (musical), 1938
      - Pomare, Eleo, 1969-1970)
      - Powell, Richard J., 1989-1999
      - Primus, Pearl, circa 1930-2000 (18 folders)
      - Q's Jook Joint (musical recording) liner notes, 1995
      - Race Riots, Detroit, MI, 1943 (2 folders)
      - Race Riots, Harlem, New York, Harlem, 1943
      - Ragtime dance and music, 1974-1994
      - Robeson, Paul, circa 1940-1959
      - Shawn, Ted: Cane Cutting Dance, circa 1930-1939
      - Social Dance photographs, 1939
      - Solomons, Gus, Jr., circa 1970-1999 (2 folders)
      - Southern States, Civilization, 1989
      - St. Denis, Ruth, Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, circa 1930-1939
      - Tamiris, Helen, 1936, 1998-1999 (2 folders)
      - Tap Dancing, 1988-1999 (Box 10)
      - Theater, African-Americans, 1985, 1998 (2 folders)
      - Thompson, Clive, circa 1950-1989
      - Urban Bush Women, circa 1997-1998
      - Vaudeville, 1998
      - Wigman, Mary, circa 1930-1949, 1998